# HIMANSHU RAWAT

## DIGITAL MARKETING EXECUTIVE

## **OBJECTIVE**

To utilize my knowledge of digital marketing and skills in developing effective marketing strategies to drive business growth and improve customer engagement. I am passionate about utilizing the latest digital technologies and trends to create compelling content, enhance user experience, and maximize ROI for the organization."

### **EDUCATION**

Indra Gandhi National Open University

 Persuing Bachelor of Commerce 2020/2023

Kerala Education Society Senior Secondary School

- 12th Passed CBSE Board 2020
- 10th Passed CBSE Board 2018

## **PERSONALITY TRAITS**

- Proactive
- Disciplined
- Detail Oriented
- Flexible
- Process Oriented

### **LANGUAGES**

- English Proficiency
- · Hindi Proficiency

## **CONTACT**

- **(**) 7<u>982837274</u>
- hirawat2002@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/hirawat2002

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- 1. Social Media Optimisation (SMO)
- 2. Search Engine Marketing (SEM)
- 3. Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)
- On-Page Optimisation
- Google Webmaster
- Off-Page Optimisation
- 4. Email Marketing
- 5. Online Reputation Management (ORM)
- 6. Video Marketing

### **TOOLS**

- Canva
- WordPress/HTML
- Semrush/Ahrefs
- Google Analytics/Search Console/Google Cloud/ Google AdWords

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **SEO Executive** (May 2023 - Present) *PNJ SharpTech*, *Noida*

- Worked on multiple projects, including in-house as well as the company's projects, and also developed and implemented good and effective SEO strategies to improve website traffic.
- Conducted thorough keyword research and analysis to identify high-potential keywords for optimization.
- Optimized website content and meta tags for targeted keywords to improve search engine visibility.
- Utilized Google Analytics and Search Console to track website traffic and performance.
- Used Meta Business Suite and Responsible for managing all social media handles of clients as well as company to increase engagement and reach.
- Coordinating with the designers and Content writers for creatives, Featured images and content publishing
- Conducted link building and backlink analysis to improve domain authority .
- handling interns to guide and help them achieve the required goals.

## **SEO Trainee** (Nov 2022 - May 2023) BW Businessworld Pvt. Ltd, Connaught Place

- Developed and implemented good and effective SEO strategies to improve website traffic from 1.97 Lakh to 5.1 Lakh and boost search engine rankings.
- Conducted thorough keyword research and analysis to identify high-potential keywords for optimization.
- Optimized website content and meta tags for targeted keywords to improve search engine visibility.
- Utilized Google Analytics and Search Console to track website traffic and performance.
- Managed social media accounts to promote website content, events and increase online engagement.
- Managed and promoted more than 10 events for the company over LinkedIn and other Social Media Platforms..
- Coordinating with the designers and editorials for creatives, banners, and content publishing
- Conducted link building and backlink analysis to improve domain authority (73-75).

## Digital Marketing (Dec 2022 - Nov 2022)

#### Freelance

- Responsible for improving the social media presence and reach of the posts for clients.
- Creating a blogging and service website for clients using WordPress and Shopify
- To look over the on-page SEO and technical SEO aspects of websites too.
- Producing new content as well as posting it yourself with the help of tools like Canva, Photoshop, and Premier Pro.
- Used tools like Meta Business Suite and YouTube Studio to track the campaigns and analytics of social media.
- Also used Google Analytics to track traffic for websites and Google Search Console to track the issues and overall health of the websites.

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Represented School in Football Competition in Year 2017 & 2019
- Represented School in Kabbadi Competition in Year 2016 & 2018
- Also participated in various activities like singing, dancing and marathon during Schooling Years.

## **HOBBIES**

- Sports Activities
- Music
- Content Creation
- Singing

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

• Name: Himanshu Rawat

• Father's Name: Girish Singh Rawat

• Date of Birth: 28/09/2002

• Gender: Male

Relationship : SingleNationality : Indian

### **DECLARATION**

I hereby declare that the details and information given above are complete and true to the best of my knowledge.

## Date:

## Signature Place :